# Anthony Ferguson Jr.

978 Karshick St., Bohemia, NY 11716 516-457-7034 | aferguson778@gmail.com

afergusonjr.com | linkedin.com/in/anthony-ferguson-jr-developer | github.com/Ender778

# **Professional Summary**

Developer with over eight years of experience. I have a broad range of skills and proven leadership capabilities while learning and adapting to any situation. I always keep up on the latest technologies and UI/UX concepts/designs, while my greatest strengths lie in identifying and fixing problems.

### **Skills**

- HTML5/CSS3, JavaScript and JQuery
- VBScript, Java, C#, MySQL, ASP, JSON
- Frameworks & Libraries: D3, Bootstrap, AJAX
- IBM WCM, Documentum, Teamsite

- Jira, ALM, Trello, GitHub Desktop, SourceTree
- Adobe Products, Microsoft Office suite, VS Code, Figma
- Google Tag Manager, Google Analytics 360, WebTrends, IBM Core Metrics

## Experience

### Canon U.S.A., Inc. (Melville, NY)

Front End Web Developer, Sr. Specialist

Jan. 2018 - Present

- Lead a team for content migration, UI/UX and Development on a new portal for dealers on IBM WCM, while utilizing Jira and ALM for user stories and QA.
- Coordinate between business, IT and product groups to resolve issues, ensure smooth data transfer, and create a tailored look for a dealer audience.
- Developed real time monitors using D3, AJAX, HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript to provide up to date reporting on sales and web traffic.
- Architected and created a custom project management web application.
- Build multiple landing pages from scratch that exist on corporate site, create custom solutions for large data handling on pages including JSON file reads through AJAX.

#### Web Maintenance, Specialist

Nov. 2015 - Jan. 2018

- Upload content, manage and maintain Dealer Extranet site for all Canon dealers through Teamsite.
- Formed and lead a special projects team to help create solutions for the company utilizing the skills of fellow coworkers at no extra cost to the company.
- Create multiple VBA macros in excel to streamline reporting.
- Developed creative solutions around complex constraints to create Microsites in a 14+ year old system.
- Managed multiple interns, teaching them about business, coding and life skills.

#### Web Developer, Consultant

Mar. 2015 - Nov. 2015

- Assisted with content migration and UI/UX upgrades to the corporate website.
- Created multiple stand-alone pages in HTML5/CSS3 for product groups inside of Documentum.
- Helped launch new products on the main consumer site.

#### MKTG Inc. (East Islip, NY)

Programmer

Aug. 2012 - Mar. 2015

- Created and managed online surveys.
- Programmed in HTML5, CSS3, VBScript, JQuery and JavaScript for frontend development.
- Manipulated template data to make custom surveys look and work to client specifications.
- Compile, extract, and modify data from surveys using SQL statements and VBScript macros in Excel.
- Worked on multiple projects at once while managing my time effectively.

# Education

### SUNY Old Westbury

Old Westbury, New York

May 2011

- B.S., Computer and Information Science (3.3 GPA)
- Key classes:
  - o System Design, Software Engineering, Internet and Web Technology, Data Structures and Algorithms
- Key Skills:
  - o Java, JSP, JDBC, MySQL, JavaScript, HTML/XHTML, AJAX, CSS, Netbeans/Eclipse

### **Honors**

#### Canon U.S.A., Inc. (Melville, NY)

Canon Spirit Award Winner

2017

- Out of all the employees for Canon Americas, only 25 won this award for the year.
- Represents only select employees who went above and beyond in their job and are nominated by their peers.

#### Canon America President Award - Finalist

2018

- The CAPA awards are presented to those involved in projects that have significant impact on the business
- Went against over 100 submissions and won the finalist spot for the creation of our real time ecommerce monitors